# Ilya Yakubovich

CONTACT Information 20 Thorny Brae Dr. Thornhill

ON L3T3G3 E-mail: ilya.yakubovich@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I'm a Human/Computer Interaction designer with a computer science background and over 6 years of experience in development, product management, and user experience design. Please view my portfolio for examples of work, and an outline of my design process.

Phone: (647) 523-7342

Portfolio: http://yak.nu

#### EXPERIENCE

#### Yammer, Inc.

Product Manager / Lead User Experience Designer

2008 - 2011

- Yammer is an enterprise social networking solution that connects employee communities within large organizations.
- As a member of the founding team, I designed a product that is now used at over 100,000 businesses worldwide.
- $\bullet$  Created mockups (Omnigraffle) and high-fidelity comps (Photoshop).
- Wrote feature specifications and design documents.
- Implemented user-facing features in HTML, CSS, and Ruby on Rails.
- Worked with developers during the implementation phase.
- Set up and maintained a ticketing system (JIRA).
- Set up and analyzed A/B tests to measure the impact of new features.
- Participated in the Quality Assurance process.

### Geni, Inc.

Product Manager

2007 - 2008

- Geni is a collaborative genealogy tool that is used by over 6 million users.
- Brainstormed new feature ideas with the product team.
- Created mockups and high-fidelity comps.
- Wrote feature specifications and design documents.
- Worked with developers during the implementation phase.

#### Device Scientific Inc.

Software developer

2006

- Implemented Linux device drivers for new linescan camera device (C++, ARM Linux).
- Interfaced Linux hardware and a .NET application on a host machine.
- Wrote a testing and debugging harness for hardware, and assisted in the hardware debugging process.
- Worked in a distributed team of 5 developers.

# NSIX Vision Inc.

Designer / Developer

2006

- Designed and implemented a website for a consulting startup.
- Developed dynamic web-pages (HTML, CSS, ASP, SQL server).
- Designed logos and slideshow presentations.

# York University Computer Club

President 2006 — 2008

- Set up and maintained Linux, BSD and Solaris servers and workstations.
- Tutored first and second year CS students.
- Created educational materials for first year CS students.

### Irina Guletsky, PhD

Software developer

2005

- $\bullet$  Designed and implemented C# application used as a tool for music theory research.
- The application involved data entry, data analysis and graphical output (representation of researched musical patterns).

EDUCATION

York University Toronto, Ontario

BSc, Computer Science, 2008

Thornhill Secondary Secondary (TSS) Toronto, Ontario

OSSD, June 2004

SKILLS

Tools: Omnigraffle Pro, Photoshop CS4/CS5, Illustrator CS4/CS5, VIM.

**Programming Languages:** Ruby on Rails, C, Java, HTML, CSS, Javascript, git. **Operating Systems:** Developed for Microsoft Windows and Linux. Advanced OS X

user.

Languages: English, Hebrew and Russian.